zambiawatchdog.com 2018-10-27

# Privacy - Zambian Watchdog

Zambian Watchdog is fully committed to protecting your privacy using technology that gives you a safe online experience.

This Privacy Policy applies to the Zambian Watchdog website (the ‘Website’) and governs data collection and usage. By using the Website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement.

### Data collection

Zambian Watchdog collects personally identifiable information when users submit comments, register and are logged into the Website. We also collect anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you.

There is also information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by the Website using software such as Google Analytics. This information can include your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring website addresses. This information is used by Zambian Watchdog for the operation of the Website, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the Website.

Zambian Watchdog tracks the pages that users of the Website visit within the Website.

### Use of your personal information

Zambian Watchdog does not sell, rent or lease its customer or user lists to third parties. We may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique personally identifiable information is not transferred to the third party. In addition, we may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support or arrange for delivery of services such as online advertising. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

### Security of your personal information

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through the Website, this information may be collected and used by others although Zambian Watchdog does make endeavours to ensure your personally identifiable data is not intercepted.

The Website secures your personal information from unauthorised access, use or disclosure. The Website secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorised access, use or disclosure.

Zambian Watchdog will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Zambian Watchdog; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Zambian Watchdog; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of the Website, or the public.

### Third party websites

We encourage you to review the privacy statements of websites you choose to link to from the Website so that you can understand how those websites collect, use and share your information. Zambian Watchdog is not responsible for the privacy policies or other content on third party websites.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

Zambian Watchdog may occasionally update this Privacy Policy. We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Policy to be informed of how Zambian Watchdog is protecting your information.

If you believe that we have not adhered to this Privacy Policy, please contact us. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem.
